A Guide to the Papers of Ellen Glasgow
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #10137-b
Ellen Glasgow Papers ca. 1877-1974
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
10137-b
ca. 200 items
Josephine Glasgow Clark
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Josephine Glasgow Clark, 20 North Laurel Street, Richmond, Virginia, 23220, 14 Oct 1976
Container List
- Mrs. Francis T. Glasgow to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1892 Jan 1; AN, 2 p. on calling card
- Poem, "To Josephine" by Ellen Glasgow, ca. 1898; AMs
- Bound volume of printed photographs of paintings by old masters assembled for, and inscribed to, Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1901 Jan, by her aunt Ellen Glasgow["Lellie"], with the names of the artists, their schools, and dates written throughout in the hand of Ellen Glasgow, ca. 1901 Jan; Bound volume
- Mary Johnston, Cairo, Egypt, to Cary Glasgow McCormack, [1909] Jan 29; APCS
- Mary Johnston, Egypt, to Ellen Glasgow, 1909 Feb 1; APCS
- Mary Johnston, Clovelly, England, to Cary Glasgow McCormack, 1909 July 28; APCS
- Clare de Graffenried, Russia, to Cary Glasgow McCormack, 1909 Aug 6 and Sept 14; 2 APCS
- Mary Johnston, Grasmere, England, to Cary Glasgow McCormack, 1909 Aug 17; APCS
- Arthur Glasgow to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1926 July 14; TLS, 1 p.
- Mary Johnston, Venice, Italy, to Ellen Glasgow, [1909?] Sept; APCS
- Mary Johnston to Ellen Glasgow, a picture of William Blake's "Mirth and her Companions", [1909?]; APCS
- Arthur Graham Glasgow to [Josephine Glasgow Clark re Ellen Glasgow's death, [1945 Nov 22]; TLS, 1 p.
- Marjorie Glasgow Congreve to Josephine Glasgow Clark expressing sorrow at the death of Ellen Glasgow, 1945 Nov 27; ALS, 4 p. on 2 1. w/env.
- Christmas card containing ALS, [1945 Dec], from Roberta Wellford to Josephine Glasgow Clark expressing sorrow at the death of Ellen Glasgow, ALS
- Printed card containing poem for Ellen Glasgow, courtesy of the National Humane Review, [ca. 1945]; Printed card
- The Woman's Club Bulletin, Richmond, Virginia, Vol. XI, No.2, 1946, containing a 4-page memorial tribute to Ellen Glasgow, Bulletin
- Douglas N. Maynard to Josephine Glasgow Clark, enclosing a carbon typescript of message from Ellen Glasgow, 1934 or 1935, "To the Members of the Richmond Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals", 1947 Jan 30; TLS, 2 p. on 2 1.
- Francis W. Hatch, "Castine-Historic Gem of Penobscot Bay," reprinted from Down East, July 1971, [1971 July]; Printed material
- Francis W. Hatch to Josephine Glasgow Clark re Ellen Glasgow's life in Castine, Maine, 1973 Mar 9; TLS, 2 p. on 1 1.
- Francis W. Hatch to Josephine Glasgow Clark re Ellen Glasgow's life in Castine, Maine, 1973 June 12; TLS, 2 p. on 1 1.
- Francis W. Hatch to Josephine Glasgow Clark re Ellen Glasgow's life in Castine, Maine, with snapshot view of two spruce trees from Ellen Glasgow's bedroom in Castine, 1973 June 25; TLS, 1 p. w/env.
- Material pertaining to the 100th anniversary of the birth of Ellen Glasgow and the symposium held in her honor at Mary Baldwin College, Staunton, Virginia, 1973 Oct 19 and 20, 21 items
- Down East, June 1974, containing Francis W. Hatch's article, " Ellen Glasgow: Pulitzer Prize-Winner at Castine", [1974 June]; Printed material
- Ellen Glasgow to Josephine Glasgow Clark, with autograph message signed, n.d.; Christmas card
- signed " Majorie [Kinnan] Rawlings", n.d.; Christmas card
- signed " Marjorie K[innan] R[awlings]", n.d.; Gift card
- Book plate of Ellen Glasgow
- ca. 133 newspaper and magazine clippings containing reviews of books by Ellen Glasgow and articles pertaining to her life and career
- Ellen Glasgow in the pink coat and bonnet she describes in The Woman Within, ca. 1877; Photograph
- "Uncle Will," the Glasgow Family servant, taken at "Jerdone Castle," Louisa County, Virginia, 1886 or 1887; Photograph
- Ellen Glasgow, Cary Glasgow McCormack, and Rebe Glasgow Tutwiler in Egypt, 1899; Photograph
- Cary Glasgow McCormack on camel-back in Egypt, 1899; Photograph
- Ellen Glasgow taken in the garden of her house in Barnstable, Cape Cod, Massachusetts, 1925; 8 snapshots
- Ellen Glasgow as a young woman, n.d.; Framed oval portrait photograph
- Woodcut by [Lankes?] of Ellen Glasgow's house in Richmond, inscribed "For Josephine [Glasgow Clark]- The old house in Richmond/ Ellen Glasgow", Framed woodcut
- Ellen Glasgow's house in Richmond, ante 1945; Postcard picture
- "Green Forest," Buena Vista, Virginia, the birthplace of Francis Thomas Glasgow, n.d.; Postcard picture
- "Jerdone Castle," Louisa County, Virginia, the Glasgow Family summer home, n.d.; Photograph
- Cary Glasgow McCormack at Warm Springs, Virginia, n.d.; Photograph
- Cary Glasgow McCormack and Roberta Wellford at Warm Springs, Virginia, Photograph